Guide to the Vera Rony Papers TAM.593
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Vera Rony Papers
1904-2009
1950-2004
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Rony, Vera
TAM.593
47 Linear Feet in 60 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, 1 quarter manuscript box, 1 audiocassette box, and 1 card box
29 videocassettes
38 audiocassettes
Vera Rony was an educator; writer; and labor, union, and civil rights advocate. In 1952, she began her career at the International Ladies Garment Workers Union (ILGWU) and went on to become the executive director of the Workers Defense League (WDL). Additionally, Rony participated in the civil rights movement in the South, publishing a number of articles on the relationships between unions and civil rights. Rony served as the Founding Director and first Affirmative Action Officer of the Labor Management Studies Program at Stony Brook University. She was the Executive Producer of The Uprising of '34, a 1995 PBS documentary that explores the 1934 General Textile Strike in which 500,000 Southern mill laborers walked off their jobs. The bulk of the Vera Rony Papers relate to her work with different labor organizations, the making of the film, and her writing, all of which are closely related because of her focus on the history of labor movements in the South. Materials include correspondence, research material for her writing and the film, drafts and notes for published and unpublished writing, videotapes of the film, and audiocassettes of interviews used in the film.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the Estate of Vera Rony Kristein in 2011 and 2012. The accession numbers associated with this collection are 2011.127 and 2012.003.
Appraisal
A list of deaccessioned books, journals, and magazines is available in the collection file. Two floppy disks were deaccessioned: one was demagnetized and the other was a duplicate of existing paper material.
Arrangement
The records are arranged into five series, one of which has been further arranged into subseries. The series and subseries arrangement of the records is as follows:
Series I. Personal
Series II. Academic and Organizational Positions
Series III. The Uprising of '34
Series IV. Writing
Subseries IV.A Published
Subseries IV.B Unpublished
Series V. Subject Files
The contents of each series or subseries are arranged chronologically with the exceptions of Series III (The Uprising of '34), which is arranged alphabetically by topics (such as Correspondence, Fundraising, and Grants, among others); and Series V (Subject Files), which is arranged alphabetically by last name, organization name, or topic.
Biographical Note
Vera Rony (1918-2011) was an educator; writer; and labor, union, and civil rights advocate.
Rony was born in Hungary in 1918. After coming to America in the 1920s, her father, Hugo Rony, became a medical doctor and her mother, Pauline (also known as Palko), took care of the household. Rony received her bachelor's degree from University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill in 1940, and her master's degree from the University of Chicago in 1969.
In 1952, she began her career at the International Ladies Garment Workers Union (ILGWU), where she founded the education department of the Beltmakers Union and instituted night classes, a library, and a political action program. From 1956-1964, she was the executive director of the Workers Defense League (WDL), a workers' rights organization founded in 1936; her accomplishments included the organization of a training program to prepare minority youth to enter the building trades and a co-written report on how racism was used in the South to thwart union organizing efforts.
Additionally, from 1965-1969, Rony participated in the civil rights movement in the South, publishing a number of articles on the relationships between unions and civil rights. Also around this time, she worked with various organizations, including the Congress of Racial Equity (CORE), Southern Student Organizing Committee (SSOC), the Middle Tennessee Labor Conference, and the Southern Tenants Farmer Union (STFU). She most likely did not hold paid positions with these organizations, but worked as a volunteer consultant, committee member, and/or editor/contributor for publications. At the Rural Advancement Fund (part of the National Sharecroppers Fund/NSF), she chaired the Education Committee for the Frank P. Graham Rural Training Center in Wadesboro, North Carolina.
Rony began her career at SUNY Stony Brook in 1969, as the first assistant vice president of the affirmative action program. By 1978, she had founded the Labor Management Studies Program, where she served as the director until 1987. Rony also held a visiting scholar position at Georgia State University, from 1976-1978. She was the Executive Producer of The Uprising of '34, a 1995 PBS documentary that explores the 1934 General Textile Strike in which 500,000 Southern mill laborers walked off their jobs. In 1995, the documentary won the Oral History Association Award for Nonprint Media for George Stoney and Judith Helfand, co-directors and co-producers, and Vera Rony, executive producer. Rony died on June 2, 2011, after a brief struggle with lymphoma.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596, with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Scope and Contents
The Vera Rony Papers (1865-2009) consist of materials created and collected by Rony documenting her life as, in her own words, a "participant observer," or someone who alternates between the worlds of academia and grassroots fieldwork. The bulk of the collection relates to her work with different labor organizations, the making of the film, and her writing, all of which are closely related because of her focus on the history of labor movements in the South. She spent many years researching and writing on the topic, beginning in the 1960s, which seemed to culminate in the film and a never-published book, "True South." The collection contains news clippings, publications, printed ephemera, correspondence, and research files related to Rony's work at Stony Brook, the Workers Defense League (WDL), National Sharecroppers Fund (NSF), and other groups; Rony's published and unpublished writings; research, publicity, and administrative files for The Uprising of '34; VHS tapes and audiocassettes of interviews, mostly related to the film; and personal correspondence and photographs.
This collection documents the history of labor, unions, and civil rights movements in the United States, particularly in the South, in the 1950s-1970s. The collection is especially relevant to researchers interested in the activities of organizations such as the WDL and NSF, the agricultural and textile industries, racism, poverty, and the development and curricula of labor management studies programs.
Affirmative action programs -- United States; African Americans and labor unions; Agricultural laborers |x Labor unions |z United States.; Civil rights movements -- United States -- History -- 20th century.; Documentary films; Labor disputes -- United States.; Labor -- History; Labor movement -- United States -- History; Labor unions; Strikes and lockouts -- Textile industry -- Southern States; Textile industry.; Textile workers -- Labor unions.; Textile Workers' Strike, Southern States, 1934; Women in the labor movement -- United States; Rony, Vera; Stoney, George C.; National Sharecroppers' Fund (U.S.); Stony Brook University; Textile Workers Union of America; Workers' Defense League
- Series I. Personal, 1918-2009; 2.19 Linear Feet in 5 manuscript boxes
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of personal and biographical materials. These materials encompass Rony's early life and family through correspondence, her father's diaries, and photographs; her daily activities through daily calendars; awards for her contributions to the field of labor history; and her personal relationships with friends through correspondence. Insight into Rony's interests in labor history, leftist politics, and civil rights can be gleaned from her father's diaries; both of Rony's parents were Hungarian Jews, and as her father describes, he was a Socialist and atheist by age 14.
  - Birth Certificate (Copy) and Translation, 1918-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Rony, Hugo (Father) -- Correspondence, 1919-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Family Photographs, 1924-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Rony, Pauline (Mother) -- Correspondence, 1948-1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Rony, Vera -- Photographs, circa 1950-1999 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Wiggins, Lee M. -- Divorce Papers, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Rony, Hugo -- Diaries, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Kavka, Selig J. -- Eulogy for Hugo Rony, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Rony, Vera, et al. -- Eulogies for Pauline Rony, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Kristein, Marvin -- Wedding, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Last Will and Testament, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Printed Matter, 1957-1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Daily Calendars and Addresses, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Daily Calendars and Addresses, 1983-2009 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Workers Defense League Award, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - New York Labor History Award, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Awards -- General, 1984-1995 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence -- Auerbach, Betts and Lennie, 1964-1992 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence -- Benson, Herman, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence -- Carr, Clare, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence -- Lamb, Kathy and Robert, 1995-1998 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence -- Newlin, Sara and Paul, 1994-1999 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence -- Rogers, Tom, 1990-1997 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence -- Silber, Priscilla Yard and Family, circa 1986-1999 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence -- Speer, Robert, 1937-1958 (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence -- Weyl, Muriel, 1972-2006 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence -- Wiggins, Lee M., 1940-1990 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence -- General, 1943-1982 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence -- General, 1983-1989 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence -- General, 1990-1995 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence -- General, 1996-2005 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence -- General, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Series II. Academic and Organizational Positions, 1954-2003; 4.15 Linear Feet in 9 manuscript boxes and 1 small box; 1 audiocassette
  This series focuses on Rony's work with various labor organizations and her career at Stony Brook University. Her work with WDL, NSF, and STFU, among others, reflects her expertise in the Southern labor movement and labor history in general. Her interest in civil rights, especially those related to labor and unions, is reflected in the materials from the SSOC, where she possibly worked as a seminar speaker, and the correspondence files, in which she corresponded with the various publishers about the series of articles that she wrote in the mid-late 1960s. Her success in creating an academic program of study on labor is reflected in her career at SUNY Stony Brook, where she instituted the affirmative action program, founded the Center for Labor/Management Studies, and taught. Materials in this series include correspondence; meeting minutes and agendas; memos; publications (newsletters, press releases, and reports) from the organizations; reappointment materials for her position at Stony Brook; a report on the Labor/Management Studies program; and syllabi and lecture notes for Stony Brook and Georgia State University. In addition, there is a file on Rony's conference and event talks and speeches, which includes an audio recording of her participation in "Women, Work, and Dollars," in 1980.
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1955-1998 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - ID Cards, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence -- The Free Press, 1963-1984 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence -- Friedman, Fred, 1978-2003 (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
  - Correspondence -- Georgia State University, 1975-1982 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence -- The New York Times, 1965-1995 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence -- Quadrangle Books, Inc., 1963-1969 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence -- The Reporter, 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence -- General, circa 1954-2003 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Professional Contacts, 1965-1998 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Workers Defense League, 1957-1998 (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
  - Congress of Racial Equality (CORE), 1964-1966 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Southern Student Organizing Committee (SSOC), circa 1965-1969 (Box 6, Folder 6, Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Middle Tennessee Labor Conference, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Southern Labor Action Movement (SLAM), circa 1967 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - National Sharecroppers Fund (NSF), 1965 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - NSF, 1966-1971 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - NSF, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - NSF, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - NSF, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - NSF, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
  - NSF, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 5, Box 9, Folder 1)
  - NSF, 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - NSF, 1980-1985 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Southern Tenant Farmers Union (STFU), 1967-1988 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Stony Brook University -- Administrative, 1969-1971 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Stony Brook University -- Administrative, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Stony Brook University -- Administrative, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Stony Brook University -- Administrative, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
  - Stony Brook University -- Administrative, 1976-1979 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Stony Brook University -- Administrative, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Stony Brook University -- Administrative, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Stony Brook University -- Administrative, 1984-1986 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Stony Brook University -- Administrative, 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Stony Brook University -- Administrative, 1989-1999 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Stony Brook University -- Lecture Materials, 1970-1977 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Stony Brook University -- Lecture Materials, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 4-5)
  - Stony Brook University -- Lecture Materials, 1979-1982 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Stony Brook University -- Lecture Materials, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Stony Brook University -- Lecture Materials, 1984-1986 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Conference and Event Participation, 1973-1986 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - "Women, Work and Dollars" with Vera Rony and Barbara Gore, April 4, 1980 (Box 26, Audiocassette 593_0064)
- Series III. The Uprising of '34, 1928-2002; 5.96 Linear Feet in 11 manuscript boxes, 1 small half-manuscript box, 1 flat box, and 1 small box; 27 VHS; 37 audiocassettes
  This series consists of materials on the documentary, The Uprising of '34. This series reflects her lifelong passion for labor history, especially the Southern textile industry. Rony began interviewing people in the 1960s, most likely while she was writing about the civil rights movement, and continued gathering interview and research material through the 1990s. She also organized a research consortium in 1984-1985, in order to interview survivors of the strike which led to the making of a short film. This film helped her to persuade George Stoney, a NYU filmmaker, to direct the documentary. Materials include correspondence with the members of the consortium and Stoney, Consortium meeting minutes, transcripts and audiocassettes of interviews, various notes (both handwritten and typed), publicity materials (such as reviews and flyers), financial documents (budgets, fundraising efforts, and grant applications), research materials (including videocassettes and newsreels on the strike), drafts of the script, videocassettes of the film (including promotional videos, samplers, and rough cuts), and a study guide for schools, which was generated after the release of the film in 1995.
  - Early Notes and Proposal for Publication on the Uprising of 1934, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Formation of Consortium, 1984-1985 (Box 13, Folder 5-6)
  - Consortium Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Consortium Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Consortium Correspondence, 1990-1995 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Consortium Members, circa 1985-1993 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Consortium Reports, 1986-1995 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence -- Hard Times Productions, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence -- Stetin, Sol, 1981-2000 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence -- Stoney, George, 1988-2002 (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence -- General, 1984-1999 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Filmmakers' Resumes, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Financials, 1987-1993 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Fundraising, 1988-1994 (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
  - Fundraising Consultant -- Spencer, Robert, 1988-1990 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Fundraising Consultant -- Miller, Peter, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Grants -- Correspondence, 1990-1996 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Grants -- Alabama Humanities Foundation, 1989-1990 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Grants -- Atran Foundation, 1989-1992 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Grants -- Botein, Hays, and Sklar, 1987-1993 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Grants -- Georgia Humanities Council, 1989-1990 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Grants -- Kentucky Foundation for Women, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Grants -- Letters of Support, 1989-1991 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Grants -- National Endowment for the Humanities, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Grants -- New York Foundation for the Arts, 1990-1991 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Grants -- North Carolina Humanities Council, 1989-1990 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Grants -- South Carolina Humanities Council, 1989-1991 (Box 17, Folder 8, Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Grants -- Southern Humanities Media Fund, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Grants -- Tennessee Humanities Council, 1989-1991 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Photographs for Film by Dan Kazimierski, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Publicity -- Press and Reviews, 1985-1998 (Box 18, Folder 5-6)
  - Publicity -- "Town of Silence," Mary O'Connell for Sunday Morning, April 28, 1996 (Box 25, Vhs 593_0063)
  - Publicity -- South Carolina TV's 30 Minute Discussion Following Broadcast of The Uprising of '34, with Tom Terrill, George Stoney, et al., June 2-3, 1998 (Box 23, Vhs 593_0022)
  - Publicity -- "Nothing to Fear," from ABC's The Century, with Peter Jennings, 1999 (Box 23, Vhs 593_0029)
  - Research Correspondence, 1984-1993 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Research -- Interview Transcripts and Notes, 1964-1991 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Research -- Interviews, Alvarez, Sally and Joe, Columbus, GA, 1988 (Box 25, Audiocassette 593_0040)
  - Research -- Interviews, Arnall, Ellis (Former Governor), Atlanta, GA, 1977 (Box 25, Audiocassette 593_0055)
  - Research -- Interviews, Brooke, Garland, Greensboro, GA, and Les Hough, Atlanta, GA, 1988 (Box 25, Audiocassette 593_0030-0031)
  - Research -- Interviews, Causey, Virginia, Fred Fussell, Cleveland Walton, and A. Jones, Columbus, GA, 1988 (Box 25, Audiocassette 593_0044)
  - Research -- Interviews, Cox, Burns, Yula/Ula McGill, and Ed Trammel, Gadsden, AL, 1988 (Box 25, Audiocassette 593_0035-0037)
  - Research -- Interviews, Dinwiddie, Bob, et al., Georgia Labor Archives, 1988 (Box 25, Audiocassette 593_0046)
  - Research -- Interviews, Hammett, Norman and Mary McKorckey, Honea Path, SC, 1988 (Box 25, Audiocassette 593_0045)
  - Research -- Interviews, Hobbs, Shirley, Linwood Ivey, Frances McNair, and Lundie Cannon, Roanoke Rapids, NC, 1976 (Box 25, Audiocassette 593_0057-0058)
  - Research -- Interviews, Hobby, Wilbur, Durham, NC, and Christopher Scott, Raleigh, NC, 1988 (Box 25, Audiocassette 593_0042)
  - Research -- Interviews, Hollowell, Donald and James Mackey, Atlanta, GA, 1977 (Box 25, Audiocassette 593_0061-0062)
  - Research -- Interviews, Jacobs, Joe, Atlanta, GA, 1988 (Box 25, Audiocassette 593_0032, 593_0043, 593_0053-0054)
  - Research -- Interviews, King, Lonnie and John Griffin, Atlanta, GA, 1977 (Box 25, Audiocassette 593_0052, 593_0056)
  - Research -- Interviews, Knight, Pat, Greensboro, NC, 1988 (Box 25, Audiocassette 593_0041)
  - Research -- Interviews, Manderson, Marge and John and Marian Glustrom, Atlanta, GA, 1977 (Box 25, Audiocassette 593_0047-0048)
  - Research -- Interviews, Mays, Benjamin and Muriel Lokey, Atlanta, GA, 1977 (Box 25, Audiocassette 593_0049-0050)
  - Research -- Interviews, Nixon, Karl, Newnan, GA, 1977 (Box 25, Audiocassette 593_0051)
  - Research -- Interviews, Richardson, Earl, Joe Jacobs, Jesse Ryland, and Yula/Ula McGill, Cordova, AL, 1988 (Box 25, Audiocassette 593_0033-0034)
  - Research -- Interviews, Stetin, Sol and N. Zoraich, Newark, NJ, 1976 (Box 25, Audiocassette 593_0059-0060)
  - Research -- Interviews, Terrill, Tom, Columbia, SC, and Norman Hammett, Honea Path, SC, 1988 (Box 25, Audiocassette 593_0039)
  - Research -- Interview Questionnaires, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Research Materials and Notes, 1928-1933 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Research Materials and Notes, 1934 (Box 19, Folder 5, Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Research Materials and Notes, 1935-1939 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Research Material -- Dr. Terrill's Movietone Demo, Textile Outtakes, Excerpts from "American South", 1952 (Box 24, Vhs 593_0025)
  - Research Materials and Notes, 1955-1957 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Research Materials and Notes, 1964-1969 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Research Materials and Notes, 1975-1982 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Research Materials and Notes, 1983-1993 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Research Material-- '34 Strike Newsreels, Fox/Movietone from USC, undated (Box 23, Vhs 593_0017)
  - Research Material --Radio Free Georgia Broadcasting Foundation, A Southern Profile: The Life and Times of Arthur Raper, 1986 (Box 26, Vhs 593_0065-0067)
  - Research Material -- "The Gospel According to Wayne Flynt," The University of Alabama Center for Public Television, undated (Box 24, Vhs 593_0026)
  - Research Material -- "Let Us Now Praise Famous Men Revisited," The American Experience, 1988 (Box 24, Vhs 593_0027)
  - Research Material -- "ACTWU in Action", undated (Box 24, Vhs 593_0028)
  - Research Reports, 1987-1988 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Script -- Edits, Scenarios, Notes, and Rough Cut, 1987-1993 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Script -- Treatment, Notes, and Edits, 1994 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Script -- Final Fine Cut, Non-Broadcast Version, 1994 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Study Guide, 1992-1998 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Videotape -- The Uprising of '34: An Introduction to the Proposed Feature-Length Video Documentary; 13 Minutes, Color, #R1, R3-R5, undated (Box 22, Vhs 593_0001-0002, Box 23, Vhs 593_0014-0015)
  - Videotape -- The Uprising of 1934 Video Project, Short Samplers, undated (Box 22, Vhs 593_0003, 593_0011)
  - Videotape -- 1934 General Textile Strike Promotional Video by George Stoney, undated (Box 22, Vhs 593_0004)
  - Videotape -- The Uprising of '34, Offline Rough Cuts, 25 and 63 Minutes, 1993 (Box 22, Vhs 593_0005, 593_0007)
  - Videotape -- The Uprising of 1934 Video Project, Excerpts from the Fieldcrest-Cannon Union Campaign, in Kannapolis/Concord, North Carolina, 1991 (Box 22, Vhs 593_0006, Box 23, Vhs 593_0019)
  - Videotape -- The Uprising of '34, Production Team Work Sample Reel, Research Consortium for the Southwide General Textile Strike of 1934, 44 Minutes, #S1-S2, S4-S5, undated (Box 22, Vhs 593_0008-0010, 593_0012)
  - Videotape -- Uprising of '34 by George Stoney, Judith Helfand, and Susanne Rostock, "For Preview Use Only," 90 Minutes, from Independent Television Service, undated (Box 22, Vhs 593_0013, Box 23, Vhs 593_0020)